A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Political Albums and photographs, Series 7 FA460
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Political Albums and photographs, Series 7
1945-1976
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller)
FA460
3.93 Cubic Feet 3 record storage cartons.
Related Archival Materials note
Additional images of Nelson A. Rockefeller and his interests will be found in the following:
Rockefeller Family Photographs. Most of the photos of Nelson A. Rockefeller in his childhood and many photos of Nelson A. Rockefeller as an adult with his parents can be found in 1005 John D. Rockefeller Jr. Family - Children's Albums or Group Portraits. See also John D. Rockefeller Jr. - Business - 17 West 54th Street.
International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC) Archives.
Nelson A. Rockefeller papers, Art, Series C (FA340). This series documents the management of Nelson A. Rockefeller's art collection and includes photos of a portion of the works of art he owned.
Arrangement note
The Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs are arranged in the following series:
Series 1008: Nelson A. Rockefeller family. Series 2: Room 5600, Rockefeller family office. Series 3: Gubernatorial Press Office. Series 4: Gubernatorial Press Office. Series 5: Gubernatorial, Robart A. (Bob) Wands. Series 6: Vice Presidential. Series 7: Unprocessed photographs.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement note
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series:
Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: photographs. Photograghs of the New York State Power Authority not found from Box 3
Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; New York (N.Y.); Arts; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Art, Modern; Political campaigns -- United States; New York (State); State governments -- United States; Rockefeller family -- Art collections; Photographs
- Nelson A. Rockefeller - Political Albums
  - Steuben County Visit, 1965 August (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - National Governors Conference, Virgin Islands. United States, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National Governors Conference, Houston, Texas, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Campaign for Governor, New York, 1958; Water damage and warped photos (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Campaign for Governor, New York, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Campaign for Governor, New York, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Allied Chemical Tower Dedication, 1965 December 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Republican Victory Dinner, War Memorial, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sterling Winthrop Research Institute, New York, 1961 April 6 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - NY State Building Ground Breaking, Albany, 1967 June 7 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Mold on some of the photos
  - Westchester County Republican Committee Dinner, 1954 January 21 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Private Dinner at Palace of Sao Paulos, Brazil, April 10, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Biographical / Historical
    Nelson Rockefeller David Rockefeller BerentFrie
  - New York State Governor Campaign, New York and Utica, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1960 Convention-Taxpayers Group for Nelson Rockefeller (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Campaign-Governor, Jones Beach and Delhi Tech and Delaware Academy, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Presidential Campaign, New Hampshire, February 22, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Presidential Campaign, New Hampshire, February 22, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Town Meeting in Geneva New York, March 10, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Opening of New York State Building, Worlds Fair, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Campaign-Governor, Formation of an Arts and Entertainment Committee for Rockefeller, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Governor Rockefeller With Secretary of State Henry Kissinger (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Thomas E. Dewey with Happy Rockefeller (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Richard Nixon and Nelson Rockefeller Signing of the Revenue Sharing Act, October 23, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Governor Executive Mansion, Albany, New York, February 21, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Expositions, Worlds Fair Canada, Syracuse State Fair, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Astronauts (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Dedication Day M&T Plaza, Buffalo, New York, June 13, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Whitney Stakes, Saratoga Springs, New York, 1962 August 4 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - 57th Annual Governors Conference, Minneapolis Minnesota, 1965 July 29 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    Photos include Hubert Humphrey, Vice President
  - Trip to Iran, Nelson and Happy Rockefeller, October 1977 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - National Governors Conference, 1963 February 24 (Box 7)
  - Happy Rockefeller Early, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Trip to South Africa, 1956 (Box 2)
    Mold in Album Preservation issues
- Photographs from Kendall Lutkins
  Appraisal
  Folders from Kendall Lutkins, 1986 June 13.
  - Richard Nixon, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Bob Hope (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Lady Bird Johnson, Laurance and Mary Rockefeller, October 7, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Awards, Photographs of Five Rockefeller Brothers, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Beginning of the United Nations, San Francisco, California, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - President Ford Dedicating Kykuit as National Landmark, November 21, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Raising Israeli Flag at Rockefeller Center, New York, May 13, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Governor Campaign, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Campaign, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Campaign, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 36)